Steven Sullivan

Antioch, CA 94531 ssully28@gmail.com 925.234.0409

Senior Software Engineer with over 20 years of experience in the contact center, bio-pharmaceutical, real estate, publishing, fulfillment, and direct response industries. Possess strong commitment to team dynamics with the ability to contribute expertise and follow leadership directives. Thrive in a team environment as well as working independently. Highly motivated, quick learner who seeks continuous growth and challenges.

Work Experience

Client Solution Analyst

West Unified Communications - San Francisco, CA February 2016 to Present

Design, build and deliver contact center solutions • Interpret client contact center objectives translating those into an actionable plan • Utilize Javascript to enhance product features in some cases eliminating weeks of development time • Analyze contact center data to investigate reported issues • Developed scripts to generate SQL for bulk uploading data • Assist clients in translating and homogenizing data from XML data export and CDRs for loading into external systems for customized reporting • Internally provide feedback and recommendations to R&D team for product improvements • Triage support and change requests both internally and externally • Provide training for clients as well as internal new hires and support staff • Assist clients and internal technical support staff with troubleshooting

Data Engineer, Information Technology

Sullivan Associates, LLC June 2002 to Present

Independent contractor, with a focus on the bio-pharmaceutical industry • Data conversion and cleansing • Database development • Data extraction, normalization and delivery (ETL) • Data review • Develop automated data auditing processes

Senior Software Engineer

Expert Planet October 2013 to July 2015

Managed migration from custom Salesforce agent scripting system to third party scripting platform
• Manage vendors and internal technical staff • Interpret complex client specifications into agents
scripts • Develop automated scripts using Perl and SQL to perform ETL processes for fulfillment
system • Create automated reports for clients and in-house staff to monitor program performance and
other metrics using various combinations of Perl, Salesforce, SOQL and SQL • Maintain and update
automated audio file processing system which pull and convert audio files from ACD and store in AWS
S3 repositories • Maintain and run invoicing system as needed • Create and maintain monitoring
systems to handle exceptions and missing files • AWS management - set up and configure EC2, S3 and
database instances as needed

Senior Data Engineer, Engineering

LiveOps

May 2006 to October 2013

Developed, tested and implemented complex reports using Perl and SQL in Linux environment

• Maintained and extended features of ETL production system • Configured and tested delivery systems using a variety of Internet protocols (FTP, FTPS, SFTP, HTTPS) • Developed tools to improve production and simplify report generation • Utilized Mason to create custom views for in-house report monitoring • Developed a simplified automated reporting platform to fetch data from custom in-house data reporting tool • Created dashboards used by both clients and in-house agents for training and management

Data Engineer, Technology Group

ZipRealty, Inc

June 2004 to May 2006

Developed an object-oriented Perl application for automating client side handling of the data acquisition system files • Engineered Perl scripts to automate the capture of photos for real estate listings over the web • Created filters to cleanse and normalize uncontrolled real estate data using Perl and Java • Developed Windows automation programs in Visual Basic and Perl to navigate and capture real estate listing data • Developed numerous ad-hoc tools using Perl in both Linux and Windows environments • Responsible for maintaining automated production system • Designed test plan for new production system and oversaw all quality assurance testing • Created various reports to monitor daily production

Software Engineer II, Editorial Systems

The Gale Group July 2000 to June 2002

Developed intranet and web based applications for periodical processing using JSP, Java Servlets, JavaBeans, Perl, Oracle 8i, Weblogic 6.1 and Tomcat 4 • Created components for automated production system using Java and JDBC • Ported applications from Windows NT to Unix (Solaris 8) • Designed robust production reports using JSP and Perl • Enhanced several existing applications to extend functionality and increase performance • Responsible for design and construction of numerous departmental intranet pages using DHTML

Supervising Engineer

The Gale Group July 1999 to July 2000

Developed wide range of Perl applications that use relational databases (Oracle 8i), internet protocols and GUI's • Supervised six-person staff across multiple locations • Designed and maintained text conversion filters for automated production system • Re-engineered several existing conversion modules to add robust indexing • Implemented training standards for team members • Assisted in troubleshooting production support

Software Engineer, Editorial Systems

Information Access Company August 1996 to July 1999 Developed Perl scripts to convert uncontrolled data sets to XML • Worked with a diverse group of engineers to maintain and further develop numerous systems and processes • Created scripts to automate testing

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

University of Phoenix September 2007

Object Oriented Analysis and Design

Thomson University June 2000

Java, Perl

U.C. Berkeley June 1998

Skills

Perl (10+ years), SQL (10+ years), ETL (10+ years), Javascript (3 years), Regular Expressions (10+ years), Linux (10+ years)